KIMULI NTEZA

Austin, Texas | (720) 635-1418 | kcnteza@gmail.com www. Linkedin.com/in/Kimuli Nteza

OBJECTIVE

To improve the company's products through enhanced quality standards by deploying strong, long-term QA integration strategies.

SUMMARY

With over 6 years of Quality Assurance experience, I have developed strong analytical, critical thinking skills, problem-solving and attention to detail.

Working in an Agile environment collaborate with cross-functional teams, Product Managers, Developers and other stakeholders, I defined test methodologies, designed test plans and test cases and raised attention to critical bug defects before the product was released to end users. These processes involved use of Confluence, Quip, Google Sheets and several internally used test management tools that are similar to Jira and Azure DevOps.

SKILLS

Interpret Software Specifications & User Requirements – Writing Test Cases & Test Scripts - Test reporting – Software Development Life-Cycle - Agile Scrum environment - Jira – Design & Production Validation Testing – Firmware – Test planning – Process Documentation - Smoke testing – Exploratory testing - User Acceptance testing (UAT) - End to end testing – System integration - root cause analysis - Mobile application testing - iOS apps – Selenium Web Automation – Selenium Python Framework Design - Confluence - SQL queries- RDBMS – Version control - Slack

EXPERIENCE

APPLE Inc.

Systems QA Engineer (Mar 2023 - Oct 2023)

- Executed user acceptance tests of iOS hardware, firmware and software following the software & product development lifecycle (EVT, DVT & PVT)
- Prepared and set up test environments to conduct user scenario tests
- Captured logs & reported test results
- Raised critical bug defects (P1) before product release to prevent costly bug leakage
- Corresponded with cross-functional teams to reproduce reported issues, update existing bugs, debug issues and run ad hoc tests

GOOGLE Inc.

Software Test Engineer (Sept 2022 - Feb 2023)

- Learnt product requirements and critical user journeys to develop test plans and execute manual test cases for web and mobile applications (iOS, Android)
- Collaborated with QA lead, Manager and developers to gather build information, set up test environments, reproduce reported bugs and resolve issues
- Applied data driven test development techniques to write manual test cases and identify automatable test scenarios.
- Performed smoke, sanity, exploratory, functional, ad-hoc, UI, and regression tests to validate software requirements on web, Android and iOS mobile devices

APPLE Inc.

QA Analyst (Sept 2021 – Sept 2022)

- Met with Program manager, Product owners, Team Lead and QA team members to gather and analyze information, ask questions and provide input on on-going and new projects
- Documented and reported data issues, specification ambiguities, procedural gaps and tool bugs using Confluence and other internal tracking tools
- Applied organizational skills by leading training and answered questions related to QA projects
- Created documentation with screenshots and workflow illustrations to supplement quality assurance training
- Provided feedback to team members and management to help improve data accuracy and content review processes

GOOGLE Inc.

QA Analyst (Mar 2018 – Jan 2019, Sep 2019 - Sep 2021)

- Reviewed and interpreted specifications and requirements for developing AI bots to support natural language processing
- Developed and implemented quality assurance metrics and testing standards
- Used AI software to generate Machine Learning training data i.e. chat bot conversations and rated bot's performance based on user inputs and returned results
- Evaluated QA team member conversation flows, structure, bot responses and user utterances to observe understood context and user intent
- Performed data integrity ivalidations, reported bugs, and delivered project analysis reports

APPLE Inc.

Maps Analyst (Feb 2019 - Sep 2019)

- Executed python automation test scripts to flag and triage errors in map files before manual verification (pass / fail criteria)
- Used internal bug tracking software to file and report map data & software bugs

- Generated QA team's productivity reports using SQL queries, Google sheets and Tableau software to reflect the team's quality score and overall productivity
- Analyzed QA results to find trends and report critical bugs
- Tested proprietary and open-source tools and applications to identify gaps in our QA process.

APPLE Inc.

GIS Analyst (Jul 2016 – Sep 2017)

- Regularly met and exceeded daily performance goals for solving user reported errors with the Apple Maps application.
- Troubleshoot reported problems to determined root causes and develop timely solutions to bugs found in Maps.
- Collaborated with small and large teams to accomplish a 98% accuracy rating in team's content quality.

EDUCATION

Selenium Web driver with Python Training via Udemy.com (Jan 2023)

- Implemented Python Test Automation Frameworks to test and automate web applications.
- Applied Selenium Python API Methods with real time Scenarios on live websites
- Logging in Python Tests
- Cross-browser testing

Software QA Training via Udemy.com (Sep 2021)

- Performed product requirements analysis, QA testing
- Created and executed unit, integration, system, and acceptance tests on live applications
- Identified and reported bugs in Jira bug tracking system

Excel to MySQL: Analytic Techniques for Business Specialization Coursera.com (Dec 2018)

Master of Science Florida International University (May 2013)

Bachelor of Arts Metropolitan State College of Denver (May 2010)